College English Test,
6, Part 2, Listening Comprehension Section A, Directions In this section, you will
hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Conversation 1 Hello, Jane.
Hello, Paul. Please come in.
I'm just getting ready to go home.
Susan is expecting me for dinner.
I wanted to be on time for a change.
Look, I'm terribly sorry to drop in at this time on a Friday, Paul, but it is rather
important. That's okay.
What's the problem?
Well, Paul, I won't keep you long.
You see, there's a problem with the exchange rates.
The Indian rupee has taken a fall on the foreign exchange market.
You see, there's been a sharp increase in India's balance of payment deficit.
I see. That's serious, isn't it?
Well, as you know, have been reports of unrest in India, and the prospects for the
rupee look pretty gloomy.
And that's going to affect us, as if we didn't have enough problems on our hands.
So I thought it would be wise to take out forward exchange cover to protect our
position on the outstanding contracts.
Just a minute.
Forward exchange cover?
Now, what does that mean exactly?
Well, it means that JL Motors enters into a commitment to sell Indian rupees at the
present rate. I see.
And how will that benefit us?
Well, JL Motors won't lose out if the Indian rupee falls further.
What will it cost, A small percentage, about 1%, and that can be built into the
price of the Well, I don't suppose there's much choice.
All right, Jane, let's put it into action.
Question 2. Why did the woman come to see the man?
Question 3. What makes the woman worry about the Indian rupee?
Question 4. What can we infer from the conversation?
Conversation 2. Charles, among other things, you're regarded as one of America's
great masters of the blues, a musical idiom that's essentially about loss,
particularly the loss of romantic love.
Why does love die?
People often get into love affairs because they have unrealistic expectations about
somebody. Then when the person doesn't turn out to be who they thought he or she
was, they start thinking, maybe I can change him or her.
That kind of thinking is a mistake because when the dust settles, people are going
to be pretty much what they are.
It's a rare thing for anybody to be able to change who they really are, and this
creates a lot of At 62, you continue to spend a large percentage of your life
touring. What appeals to you about life on the road?
Music. I don't especially love life on the road, but I figure if you're lucky enough
to be able to do what you truly love doing, you've got the ultimate in life.
What's the most widely held misconception about the life of a famous musician?
People think it's all glamour.
Actually, we have the same troubles they do.
Playing music doesn't mean life treats you any better.
How do you feel about being recognized everywhere you go?
You'd think I'd be used to it by now, but I still find it fascinating.
You go to a little town in Japan where nobody speaks English, yet they know you on
sight and know all your music.
I'm still amazed by the love people express for me and my music.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What does the man say about most people when they get into love affairs?
Question 6. What does the man say about himself as a singer on the road most of his
life? Question 7.
What do most people think of the life of a famous musician?
Question 8. How does the man feel whenever he is recognized by his fans?
Section B. Directions.
In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices,
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Passage 1.
Changing technology and markets have stimulated the team approach to management.
Inflation, resource scarcity, reduced personnel levels, and budget cuts have all
underscored the need for better coordination in organizations.
Team management provides for this coordination.
Team management calls for new skills if personnel potential is to be fully realized.
Although a team may be composed of knowledgeable people, they must learn new ways of
relating and working together to solve cross -functional problems.
When teams consist of experienced employees from hierarchical organizations who have
been conditioned to traditional organizational culture, cooperation may not occur
naturally. It may need to be created.
Furthermore, the issue is not just how the team can function more effectively, but
how it integrates with the overall organization or society that it supposedly
serves. A group of individuals is not automatically a Therefore, team building may
be necessary in order to improve the group's performance.
Cassay, an expert in this field, suggests that the cooperation process within teams
must be organized, promoted, and managed.
He believes that team cooperation results when members go beyond their individual
capabilities, beyond what each is used to being and doing.
Together, the team may then produce something new, unique, and superior to that of
any one member.
For this to happen, he suggests that multicultural managers exhibit understanding of
their own and others' cultural influences and limitations.
They should also cultivate such skills as toleration of ambiguity, persistence, and
patience, as well as assertiveness.
If a team manager exemplifies such qualities, then the team as a whole will be
better able to realize their potential and achieve their objectives.
Questions 9 to 11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9. What should team members do to fully realize their potential?
Question 10. What needs to be considered for effective team management?
Question 11. What conclusion can we draw from what Cassay says?
Passage 2. What Advertising informs consumers about the existence and benefits of
products and services and attempts to persuade them to buy them.
The best form of is probably word -of -mouth advertising, which occurs when people
tell their friends about the benefits of products or services that they have
purchased. Yet virtually no providers of goods or services rely on this alone, but
use paid advertising instead.
Indeed, many organizations also use institutional or prestige advertising, which is
designed to build up their reputation rather than to sell particular products.
Although large companies could easily set up their own advertising departments,
write their own advertisements, and buy media space themselves, they tend to use the
services of large advertising agencies.
These are likely to have more resources and more knowledge about all aspects of
advertising and advertising media than a single company.
It is also easier for a dissatisfied company to give its account to another agency
than it would be to fire its own advertising staff.
The client company generally gives the advertising agency an agreed budget,
a statement of the objectives of the advertising campaign, known as a brief, and an
overall advertising strategy concerning the message to be communicated to the target
customers. The agency creates advertisements and develops a media plan specifying
which media will be used and in which proportions.
Agencies often produce alternative ads or commercials that are pre -tested in
newspapers, television stations, etc.
in different parts of the country before a final choice is made prior to a national
campaign. Question 13.
What does the speaker say is the purpose of many organizations using prestige
advertising? Question 14.
How do large companies generally handle their advertising?
Question 15. What will advertising agencies often do before a national campaign?
In this section you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks followed by
three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D, then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a
single line through the center.
Hello everybody. It is my honor to introduce our respectable speaker for today's
lecture, Dr. Thomas Wood.
Dr. Wood has written numerous articles and books on the topic of communication and
how to communicate effectively.
Welcome, Dr. Wood.
Good morning, everyone.
I'm very glad to have a lecture with you.
Today I'd like to talk about how to communicate effectively.
Effective communication is an essential component of human relationships, whether in
the workplace, at school, among friends, between couples, or within a household.
Highly functional, successful family groups tend to be those that communicate
effectively, while the lack of such communication is frequently found in troubled
families, according to a research company.
Learning and practicing effective communication techniques is well worth the time
and effort, resulting in stronger interpersonal ties and greater familial
satisfaction. My tips are as follows.
Think first, speak later.
Few people would stand before an audience or class and present a speech without
advanced preparation.
Gathering thoughts, ideas, and information are critical for communicating in an
organized and effective way.
Setting priorities can be helpful, especially when preparing to discuss a complex
issue. Furthermore, stepping away from a problem before discussing it allows time to
gain objectivity, as well as empathy for the other person or persons involved.
Be fully present.
Effective communication is possible only in the present moment.
Bringing past conflicts into the current discussion serves only to heighten negative
emotions and be bad for a productive conversation.
A sharp focus on the topic at hand is essential for clear and effective
communication, and it is also helpful to keep outside distractions to a minimum.
Text messages, phone calls, and emails can all wait until a later time, and worries
about work, school, or other issues can be put on hold as well.
Use nonverbal cues.
Nonverbal cues, such as facial expressions, body language, and hand gestures, play
an important role in effective communication.
Just as a badly chosen word or a raised voice can upset a listener and close the
door to further dialogue, so too can an unintentionally aggressive nonverbal cue.
One way to ensure that nonverbal signals don't undermine verbal communication is to
remain calm and avoid becoming overly stressed during a discussion.
Staying calm and maintaining a comfortable amount of eye contact while respecting
personal space can increase receptivity.
Listen actively. Effective communication includes the ability to listen well.
In addition to avoiding obvious distractions, such as cell phones and using body
language to demonstrate attentiveness, it is also important to allow the other
person to finish speaking before formulating our own response.
Paraphrasing what the other person has said to make sure we have understood
correctly and refraining from offering advice unless asked to do so are two more
ways to listen effectively.
Thank you for your listening.
Hope this lecture will be helpful and you will be a better communicator.
Question 17. Which of the following is helpful for minimizing outside distractions
during communication?
Question 18. Which of the following should be avoided in order to make a
conversation smooth?
Question 19. What is essential to be a good listener?
Recording 2. Mental health is our birthright.
We don't have to learn how to be mentally healthy.
It is built into us in the same way that our bodies know how to heal a cut or mend a
broken bone. Mental health can't be learned, only reawakened.
It is like immune system of the body, which under stress or through lack of
nutrition or exercise, can be weakened, but which never leaves us.
When we don't understand the value of mental health and we don't know how to gain
access to it, mental health will remain hidden from us.
Our mental health doesn't go anywhere, like the sun behind a cloud.
It can be temporarily hidden from view, but it is fully capable of being restored in
an instant. Mental health is the seed that contains self -esteem,
confidence in ourselves, and an ability to trust in our common sense.
It allows us to have perspective on our lives, the ability to not take ourselves too
seriously, to laugh at ourselves, to see the bigger picture, and to see that things
will work out.
It's a form of innate or unlearned optimism.
Mental health allows us to view others with sympathy, if they are having troubles,
with kindness if they are in pain, and with unconditional love, no matter who they
are. Mental health is the source of creativity for solving problems, resolving
conflict, making our surroundings more beautiful,
managing our home life, or coming up with a creative business idea or invention to
make our lives easier.
It gives us patience for ourselves and toward others, as well as while driving,
catching a fish, working on our car, or raising a child.
It allows us to see the beauty that surrounds us each moment in nature, in culture,
in the flow of our daily lives.
Although mental health is the cure -all for living our lives, it is direct you
through all your difficult decisions.
Mental health has commonly been called conscience, instinct, wisdom,
common sense, or the inner voice.
We think of it simply as a healthy and helpful flow of intelligent thought.
As you will come to see, knowing that mental health is always available, and knowing
to trust it, allow us to slow down to the moment and live life happily.
20 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 20. Among humans' various abilities, which one has the same mechanism as
mental health? Question 21.
Among the following mental statuses, which can be the indication of possessing
mental health? Question 22.
Which of the following is the best title for this passage?
As career planning is very essential in your career, I would like to offer some tips
about how to do career planning.
Study yourself. This is the key to career planning.
Understanding what you are like, what you value, and what kind of person you want to
become is This foundation for all career planning.
In studying yourself, you examine your strengths and weaknesses, your goals, and the
trends in your personal development.
The self -understanding that you gain enables you to imagine how certain occupations
may best fit your personality, interests, abilities, and goals.
All career decisions require us to learn both about ourselves and about work, and to
integrate these two kinds of knowledge.
Make a list of short and long -term career goals.
Consider your individual skills, talents, interests, and hobbies.
You may realize that your daily struggle with new technologies is a source of
progress. Assign a time frame to each goal.
Some may be achievable in the near future.
Others may require years of efforts.
Many will probably lead to a series of goals that you must accomplish over time to
reach your desired end result.
If your ultimate goal is to have a managerial role, you may need to become a trainer
first, then a supervisor.
Add specific action steps to your plan that will help you to achieve each goal.
Research classes that may help you become more familiar with new technologies.
Make a list of classes that you want to take, and then schedule a time to meet with
your manager to discuss opportunities for pursuing this type of education.
Write a detailed description of your end goals for each year over the next five
years. By the end of the first year, you may want to have a few successful projects
under your belt.
As the second year comes to a close, you might want to be promoted to a higher
position and so on.
Be clear about the changes that you want to see happen, when they should take place,
and what steps you will take to get where you want to be.
Career planning does not guarantee that all the problems, difficulties, or decision
-making situations that you face in the future will be solved, nor can any formula
be given to do that.
But career planning should help you to approach and cope better with new problems,
such as whether or not to enter educational or training programs,
deciding whether or not to change jobs, and analyzing the difficulties you are
having with a situation or a person.
Questions 23 to 25 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 23. What is the fundamental step of career planning?
Question 24. According to the speaker, what should you do if your ultimate aim is
rather ambitious? Question 25.
What is the meaning of making career plans?
This is the end of listening comprehension.